Isaac Chavez

281-935-5556 | isaac-chavez.com | isaacqc0596@gmail.com | Github | Medium | Linkedin

Full-stack Software Engineer

Full-stack software engineer with experience in JavaScript/JS frameworks and server side architecture, in based programming and the implementation of Object-oriented programming. Self-motivated and possession of strong skills in critical thinking/problem solving, with an interest in how things work in unison, that helps when working with both server side and client-side languages, allowing myself to gain a better understanding and to experiment with different methods/ solutions to solve complex problems. Skills to see the big picture in terms of people, places, and needs, without compromising small details when working in a fast-paced environment, as well as collaborate/communicate well with others as a team to meet deadlines.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SASS, NodeJs, GraphQL, Apollo, Python Frameworks/Database:Rails, Express, React, React Native, NextJS, Redux, ActiveRecord, SQL/PostgreSQL, MongoDB Methodologies: Object-oriented programming(OOP), JSON, REST APIs, MVC, DRY, Scrum/Agile, Testing/Debugging, NPM, Git, Browser developer tools, Structure, Exterior design, Docker

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Interperate - Github NextJS/ReactJS, Typescript, MongoDB, SCSS, GraphQL, Apollo, Redux Work management tool to help teams efficiently track tasks/issues among other items

- JWT/bcrypt used for authentication to validate users into site and actions within site
- Modular components for reusability throughout the site, with use of custom hooks and async/await nature
- GraphQL and Apollo for query typing and state management within different components
- NextJS implemented for file/code structure

Chatter - Github MongoDB, Express, ReactJs, NodeJS (M.E.R.N) Material UI

Users are able to search and join/leave rooms, create rooms, view members, send/edit/delete messages

- Used socket.io for real time, for all changes across all users(c.r.u.d messages, online activity, leave/join rooms)
- See visibly of user when they are online & when they log off to signal other users who are online & login/signup auth
- Be able to edit messages and delete messages from only the current user who deleted it
- Implementation of react hooks for proficiency and guicker rendering

Take A Trip - Github Ruby, Rails, ReactJs, Redux, TripadviserApi, WeatherApi, Ant and Material UI

Users are able to plan trips out by searching for various things to do around their location, and may also add other users to join in on the trip to plan out more ideas

- Used Redux as a way to save state and to be accessible across different pages of the app allowing less conflict and creating a single source of truth
- Used different APIs to be able to gather data from various locations to make a more dynamic website, as well as an API to gather data on the weather for the user's location
- Able to utilize frameworks to style/design the frontend and give more functionality towards the website
- Used only functional components to be able to better understand hooks and being able to implement them

EXPERIENCE

CrouchJumpFull-Stack Software Developer

Remote 10/2020 - Present

- Assist team to structure and implement modular components, creating a more maintainable/reliable codebase to debug and update/build on top of with ease, utilizing Typescript, React/ReactNative, Redux
- Construct restful API endpoints and DB tables to proficiently communicate and guery data from and to the server
- Collaborate with team to discuss best practices using modern frameworks/techniques to efficiently meet our goals
- Preform code reviews to thoroughly learn different aspects of the codebase and facilitate knowledge from the team

Watson Grinding & Manufacturing

Houston, Texas

Abrasive Blaster/HVOF Operator

03/2017 - 02/2020

- Maximizing workflow and production by preparing parts by masking and blasting so that it may be ready to be applied with a coating
- Set up parts and write programs for which the robot may complete by recording sizes and dimensions, apply carbide
 coating, make sure gun is running smoothly by adjusting gas levels and repairing the gun parts for better
 performance, prolonging the life of hardware therefore saving and reducing company cost
- Good troubleshooting skills, ability to multitask, and good time management, consequently improving manufacturing

EDUCATION

Flatiron School
Full Stack Software Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program
Maybe Creek HighSchool
High School Diploma

Houston, Texas 03/ 2020 - 06/2020 Houston, Texas 06/ 2016